Hi and welcome. My name's David.
أهلًا ومرحبًا. أنا ديفيد.
And I'm Mat. In this course,
وأنا مات. في هذه الدورة التدريبية،
we'll be learning all about data wrangling.
سنتعلم عن تعارض البيانات.
Data wrangling is the process of gathering your data,
تعارض البيانات هو عملية جمع بياناتك،
assessing its quality and structure,
وتقييم جودتها وبنيتها،
and cleaning it before you do things like analysis,
وتنظيفها قبل أن تعمل أشياء مثل التحليل
visualization, or build predictive models using machine learning.
أو التصور أو بناء نماذج تنبؤية باستخدام التعلم الآلي.
Sometimes, it's as simple as downloading a file,
في بعض الأحيان، يكون الأمر بسيط مثل تنزيل ملف،
spotting a few typos,
وتحديد بعض الأخطاء المطبعية،
and fixing those typos.
وإصلاح تلك الأخطاء المطبعية.
But other times, your data really isn't clean.
لكن في أحيان أخرى، لا تكون بياناتك نظيفة حقًا.
That is, you'll have missing records,
بمعنى، أنه سيكون لديك سجلات مفقودة
duplicates, and inaccurate data.
ومكررة وبيانات غير دقيقة.
Sometimes, the data itself is fine but structurally,
في بعض الأحيان، تكون البيانات نفسها جيدة ولكن من الناحية الهيكلية،
it's difficult to work with.
يصعب العمل بها.
Taking care of all this is necessary or else,
إن الاهتمام بهذا أمر ضروري،
you risk making mistakes,
وإلا فإنك تخاطر بارتكاب الأخطاء
missing insights and wasting time.
وفقدان الأفكار وإضاعة الوقت.
Wrangling is a core skill that you'll use to varying degrees on
التعارض هو مهارة أساسية ستستخدمها بدرجات متفاوتة
every data set that you work with because so much of the world's data isn't clean.
في كل مجموعة بيانات تعمل معها لأن الكثير من بيانات العالم ليست نظيفة.
Fortunately, when done with code,
لحسن الحظ، عندما يتم التعامل مع الكود،
wrangling is fast and almost magical.
يكون التعارض سريعًا وسحريًا.
And by the end of this course,
بنهاية هذه الدورة التدريبية،
data wrangling will become instinctual.
سيصبح تعارض البيانات طبيعيًا.
So, are you ready to wrangle? Let's get to it.
إذًا، هل أنتم مستعدون للتعارض؟ والآن دعونا نتعرف على ذلك.